Preliminary Inventory to the Karl Christian Von Loesch Collection, 1918-1944
Hoover Institution Archives
Karl Christian Von Loesch Collection,
1918-1944
46015
Loesch, Karl Christian von, 1880-
9 manuscript boxes (3.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Pamphlets, leaflets, newspaper issues, clippings, and writings, relating to politics and elections in Germany and Austria, the German Revolution of 1918-1919, the Kapp Putsch, the Hitler Putsch, the Nazi Party, and the independent Croatian state during World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Nationalsozialistische deutsche Arbeiter-Partei.; Elections--Germany.; National socialism.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Croatia.; Austria.; Austria--Politics and government--1918-1938.; Croatia.; Germany.; Germany--History--Revolution, 1918.; Germany--History--Kapp Putsch, 1920.; Germany--History--Beer Hall Putsch, 1923.; Germany--Politics and government--20th century.; Yugoslavia.
Container List
- 1. 1919 June-December (Box 1.)
- 2. 1920
- 3. 1921
- 4. 1922
- 5. Deutschvölkischer, Schutz- und Trutzbund, 1919-1922
- 6. Deutschbund, 1922-1929
- 7. Völkische Bewegung, 1924-1925
- 8. Deutscher Tag, Nürnberg, 1923 September 1-2; Koburg, 1923 October 14-15
- 9. Völkisches, 1918-1923
- 10. Fr. Dannehl, Flugblätter, 1919
- 11. Bilderbogen, 1919
- 12. Das Gewissen (E. Stadtler,) 1919-1920 (Duplicates. For longer file see News. Coll. German Drawer)
- 13. Wirtschafts-polit. Aufbau-Korrespondenz (Scheubner-Richter,) 1923 (Box 2.)
- 14. Reichsflagge, 1925-1926; Elbwacht, 1926
- 15. Räterepublik, 1919 April 7 - Mitte Mai
- 16. Revolution in München, 1918 November 8-1919 April 6
- 17. Landtags- und Nationalversammlungswahlen, 1919 January 12-19
- 18. Berlin, Wahlen, 1919
- 19. Gemeindewahlen, München, 1919 June 15
- 20. Reichstags-und Bayr. Landtagswahlen, 1920 June 6
- 21. Reichstagswahl, 1924 May 4
- 22. Reichstags- und Stadtratswahlen, München, 1924 December 7
- 23. Bayr. Volksentscheid, 1924 April 6
- 24. Präsidentenwahl, 1925 March 29-April 26
- 25. Volksentscheid, 1926 June 20
- 26. Reichstagswahl, 1930 September 14
- 27. Bayr. Landtagswahlen, 1932 April 24, Liste 5
- 28. Preuss. Landtagswahlen, 1932 April 24, Liste 8
- 29. Präsidentenwahl, 1932 March 13
- 30. Präsidentenwahl, 1932 April 10
- 31. Reichstagswahl, 1932 July 31, Liste 2 (Box 3.)
- 32. Reichstagswahl, 1932 July 31, Berlin
- 33. Reichstagswahl, 1933 March 5
- 34. 1920, February 24
- 35. Kapp - Putsch, 1920 March 13-17
- 36. Hitler - Putsch
- 37. Programm; Satzungen, 1923
- 38. N.S.D.A.P. vor 1923 November 9
- 39. N.S.D.A.P., 1925 February 26-1935 January 29
- 40. Bayer. Mittelpartei (D.M.V.P. in Bayern); Nürnberg, 1922-1923
- 41. N.S.D.A.P. Parteitag, 1927
- 42. N.S.D.A.P. Parteitag, 1929
- 43. Sektion Westend, 1929
- 44. Mjölnir plakate, 1932
- 45. N.S.D.A.P. Hamburg, 1931-1932
- 46. N.S.D.A.P. nach 1933 January 30 (Box 4.)
- 47. N.S.D.A.P. Parteitag, 1933
- 48. N.S.D.A.P. Parteitag, 1934
- 49. N.S.D.A.P. Parteitag, 1936
- 50. München, 1938 September 29
- 51. Propaganda (vor 1927 April 15)
- 52. N.S.D.A.P. Parteiamtliches
- 53. Mein Kampf (clippings)
- 54. Horst Wessel
- 55. Plakat: "Soll Germanen Judas Sklavin sein?"
- 56. D. Eckart: Sturm-lied
- 57. N.S. Studenten
- 58. A. Drexler
- 59. Schutzstaffel
- 60. Nürnberg, 1920-1926 (Box 5.)
- 61. Arminius; Frontkrieger; Volk und Heer
- 62. Rutlischwur, 1924
- 63. Alfred Roth: Sendschreibe an den Deutschen
- 64. Hitler-Jugend
- 65. Deutsche Hochschulzeitung (Transferred. See News. Coll. Germany drawer)
- 66. Deutsche Herold; Ausschuss für Volksaufklarung. (Transferred. See S.P. Germany)
- 67. Flammenwerfen (Transferrerd. See German Serials Drawer)
- 68. Einwohnerwehr; Techn. Nothilfe
- 69. Leuchtturm, 1921-1922 (Transferred. See German Serials Drawer)
- 70. Presse Inf. Dienst 1932; "Aufklärungs und Redner Informationsmaterial", 1935-1938
- 71. Deutsches Wochenblatt, Berlin, 1921 (Transferred. See German Serials Drawer)
- 72. Die Trommel, 1924 (Duplicates. See German Serials Drawer for longer file)
- 73. Münchener Presse, 1922-19? (Transferred. See envelope for titles and German Serials Drawer for location)
- 74. Münchener Neueste Nachrichten, 1923 November 9-11. (Transferred. See News. Coll. Germany Drawer)
- 75. Völkische Provinzpresse bis 1924 (Transferred. See envelopes for titles and German Serials Drawer for location)
- 76. Berliner Arbeiterzeitung, 1927; Angriff, 1927-1929. (Transferred. See News. Coll. Germany Drawer)
- 77. Der Stürmer, 1923-1931 (Duplicates. See German Serials Drawer for longer file) (Box 6.)
- 78. Auf gut deutsch, February 2-5 (Duplicates. See German Serials Drawer for longer file)
- 79. Sontag Morgenpost, München, 1932-1933 (Transferred. See News. Coll. Germany)
- 80. Dr. Heim; Bayernbund
- 81. Münchener Burgerliche Presse, 1921 Deutsche Turnfest, 1923 (Transferred. See News. Coll. Germany)
- 84. Volk. Provinzpresse, 1926-1932 (Transferred. See envelope for titles and German Serials Drawer for location)
- 85. Weimar; Dinter; Streiter, 1924
- 86. R. Steiner; Dreigliederung, 1920
- 87. Deutsch-Sozialistische Partei
- 88. Gayr. Königsbote, 1920; varia
- 89. Varia: Bauer, Der Kompromissgeist
- 90. Bilderhefte
- 91. Bilderhefte III (Box 7.)
- 92. Braunau
- 93. Schachleitner
- 94. Oesterreich Presse, Burgerl., 1932-1938 (Transferred. See envelope for titles and German Serials Drawer for location)
- 95. Oesterreich, Völkische und N.S.D.A.P. Presse (Transferred. See envelope for titles and German Serials Drawer for location)
- 96. Oesterreich: Plakate bis 1925
- 97. Oesterreich, 1926-1938
- 98. N.S.B.O. (München), 1931
- 99. Oesterreich, 1934
- 100. Sudetenland; Oesterreich, 1938
- 101. Oesterreich; Oester Beobachter, 1938 (Transferred. See German Serials Drawer)
- 102. Oesterreich: N.S.D.A.P.
- 103. Oesterreich: kleines propaganda materiel
- 104. Oesterreich, Bohmen, Südmark